<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Martin Ferianc</title>
    <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://martinferianc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Martin Ferianc</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 18:19:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://martinferianc.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Martin Ferianc</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Bayesian Neural Networks via Algorithmic and Hardware Optimizations</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9720069/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 18:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9720069/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA-based Acceleration for Bayesian Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9743481/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 18:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9743481/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm and Hardware Co-design for Reconfigurable CNN Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9712541/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9712541/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance FPGA-based Accelerator for Bayesian Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9586137/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9586137/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Bayesian Recurrent Neural Networks on an FPGA-based Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9609847/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/9609847/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward Full-Stack Acceleration of Deep Convolutional Neural Networks on FPGAs</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/liu-2021-toward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 18:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/liu-2021-toward/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ComBiNet: Compact Convolutional Bayesian Neural Network for Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/10-1007-978-3-030-86365-4-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/10-1007-978-3-030-86365-4-39/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Performance Estimation for Design Space Exploration for Convolutional Neural Network Accelerators</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-improving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-improving/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Causal Inference for Data-free Structured Pruning</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-causal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-causal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the effects of quantisation on model uncertainty in Bayesian neural networks</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-effects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VINNAS: Variational Inference-based Neural Network Architecture Search</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-vinnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/ferianc-2021-vinnas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing FPGA-Based CNN Accelerator Using Differentiable Neural Architecture Search</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2020-optimizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2020-optimizing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Performance Estimation for FPGA-Based Accelerators for Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/10-1007-978-3-030-44534-8-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/10-1007-978-3-030-44534-8-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Block Floating-Point Quantization for Convolutional Neural Networks on FPGA</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2019-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2019-static/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F-E3D: FPGA-based Acceleration of an Efficient 3D Convolutional Neural Network for Human Action Recognition</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2019-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2019-f/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Real-Time Object Detection Accelerator with Compressed SSDLite on FPGA</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2018-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/publication/fan-2018-real/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concussion Prevention</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With concussions being reported as one of the most frequent injuries in Ice Hockey, and renewed efforts to better understand Traumatic Brain Injuries (TBI), there is demand to enhance identification of a potential injury. Studies have shown that NHL players experience an average of 1.8 concussions every 1000 hours of play and almost double that for juniors, with 12% reporting a head injury. Of these injuries sustained, over half may go unreported, demonstrating that concussions are a regular occurrence across all leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with Owen Harcombe, Alexander T. Luisi and Alexander Montgomerie-Corcoran, we developed a prototype Internet of Things product, that sits inside a player’s helmet to detect and track impacts while they are on the ice. The embedded device incorporates a gyro and accelerometer to measure these forces, and uses a WiFi enabled microcontroller to report the data back to a central server. The data is then processed and delivered to the user via an intuitive web application, making it accessible across mobile and desktop. We employed machine learning to better interpret the sensor data, and I added a unique touch by using a K-means algorithm to filter the impacts reported by the sensors, alleviating the need for long sensor calibration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of the coursework was to develop a marketing and business strategy for the prototype product. Having always been on the engineering side of product development, this was an entirely new experience, and one that I found very rewarding, as well as a skill that I would like to develop further. You can see our concept demonstration here: &lt;div class=&#34;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&#34;&gt; &lt;iframe class=&#34;embed-responsive-item&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QVr7ECA3h2E&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU Simulator/Compiler</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One part of the EIE second year Computer Architecture course was to develop, in C++, a CPU Simulator, based on the MIPS1 chip architecture. This virtual CPU was built in tandem with an automatic verification platform designed to exercise its capabilities. The deliverable had emphasis on rigorous memory management, data format encoding, including endianness as well as simulating exceptions and branch handling. The CPU and the verification platform followed a strictly defined Application Programming Interface (API) to make them portable and sustainable for potential future uses. It also enabled for my colleagues and me to test our work against each other’s frameworks, to ensure that our solutions were as rigorous as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this coursework, it was a tremendously useful exercise that taught me in greater detail about memory management in C++ and improved my general programming skills. It also solidified my understanding of basic processor architectures, particularly Reduced Instruction Set Architectures. You can try my work for yourself at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/martinferianc/CPUSimulator-EIE2&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the course, I developed a compiler that took C89 code and compiled it down to the MIPS1 Instruction set. The output of this compiler would also be simulated using QEMU but could be ported to the CPU simulator. Once again, this compiler can be found at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/martinferianc/C90Compiler-EIE2&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Marker Detection</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Novel ways to interact with computer systems, especially through motion capture and tracking, is becoming increasingly important. From information navigation to game play and even authentication, it is now more than just an idea from a James Bond movie. To continue to pursue more natural interaction, there is now a real need to develop dedicated, power efficient, embedded hardware that is streamlined for the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strive towards smarter ways to interact with a computer system formed the basis of my first-year project at Imperial College London. Alongside Alexander T. Luisi and George Punter, we developed a hardware accelerated background-subtraction algorithm, with statistical point prediction to track and act upon a user’s motion. We also developed and demonstrated a marker-based approach to highlight alternative methods to track motion using Field-Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was an excellent showcase of the power of FPGAs for real-world applications. I gained a great amount of insight into High-Level Synthesis (HLS) tools as well as the design of complex digital circuitry. I also learned about Digital-to-Analogue Converters (DACs) and Analogue-to-Digital Converters (ADCs) to be able to simultaneously control music according to the the data received from a camera module.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Marker Detection</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Novel ways to interact with computer systems, especially through motion capture and tracking, is becoming increasingly important. From information navigation to game play and even authentication, it is now more than just an idea from a James Bond movie. To continue to pursue more natural interaction, there is now a real need to develop dedicated, power efficient, embedded hardware that is streamlined for the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strive towards smarter ways to interact with a computer system formed the basis of my first-year project at Imperial College London. Alongside Alexander T. Luisi and George Punter, we developed a hardware accelerated background-subtraction algorithm, with statistical point prediction to track and act upon a user’s motion. We also developed and demonstrated a marker-based approach to highlight alternative methods to track motion using Field-Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was an excellent showcase of the power of FPGAs for real-world applications. I gained a great amount of insight into High-Level Synthesis (HLS) tools as well as the design of complex digital circuitry. I also learned about Digital-to-Analogue Converters (DACs) and Analogue-to-Digital Converters (ADCs) to be able to simultaneously control music according to the the data received from a camera module.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wells</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A healthy lifestyle should include a daily hydration routine. But, let’s be honest, in a hyper-connected world dominated by notifications, work and family life, how good are we actually at keeping track of how much water we’ve had to drink during the day? It’s a natural reflex to drink water only when thirsty, but this is not enough. In fact, doctors have shown that forgetting to stay hydrated during the day can result in reduced concentration, dizziness and fatigue, with more serious consequences of dehydration following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognizing these symptoms ourselves during busy days in College, a few of my friends and I began Wells. We developed the wellsCap, a ‘smart cap’ that would fit on a regular PET bottle, transforming it into a smart device that measures daily water intake. It securely synchronizes with an application that records and subsequently determines the ideal daily water intake based on a number of personal factors, tailoring intake specifically to an individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I constructed a unique, thermoelectric heat pump that was able to recycle the energy in the warm air escaping from a building into fresh air being drawn in. The device consisted of passive and active components, controlled by an embedded system built upon the Arduino platform. I also developed the connectivity aspects and successfully deployed the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role in the team was as the hardware engineer, responsible for product prototyping and the measurement system. I was also in charge of driving the team forward, driving our idea forward from beyond just paper. We were recognized for our efforts, coming first place at the CISCO Switch-Up Challenge in London in 2016. After a series of individual projects during high school, this experience taught me how to work in a mixed discipline team, in order to achieve the best results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZSD Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Západoslovenská Distribučná a.s. (ZSD) is the major electricity distribution company in the western part of Slovakia. More than one million households depend on ZSD for their electricity, and so to ensure that everyone stays connected to the grid, ZSD collects data by means of Smart Meters, deployed throughout western Slovakia. Data collection is nothing without data analytics and processing, and this needs to be done for each and every customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These smart meters lacked support in the ZSD’s software stack, meaning that swathes of customer data had to be stored and processed manually, costing time and money. Upon my entry to the company as an intern, I was tasked to develop a software toolbox in Java to process and format this data so that it could be imported into an existing database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was a success, and is still relied upon today- a great achievement considering that this was my first internship in a corporate environment. I learned a great deal about how to interact with other software developers and the platform’s target user base, as well as how a department functions within the wider company. ZSD’s CEO Andrej Juris summary of my internship best describes the impact of my work, “it will help our company in many ways to streamline work processes and thus contribute to significant savings in cost and time.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active and Passive Air Recuperation</title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/project/project_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Domestic heating has always been problematic. Indoor climate control had to be established to maintain comfort and prevent the spread of disease. In the late 20th Century, we began to ask ourselves about energy efficiency. What was the cost of maintaining this comfort and health? Instead of finding the one solution to solve our energy needs, what about if we looked closer, and at the energy we already have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought, “what about Energy Recuperation?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I constructed a unique, thermoelectric heat pump that was able to recycle the energy in the warm air escaping from a building into fresh air being drawn in. The device consisted of passive and active components, controlled by an embedded system built upon the Arduino platform. I also developed the connectivity aspects and successfully deployed the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in high-school, I won a gold medal at The International Sustainable World Energy, Engineering, and Environment Project Olympiad (I-SWEEEP) in Houston, Texas with this project. I also applied for, and was awarded a national patent for the device. This was the first time I was working with embedded devices- completely individually. In addition to all the technical skills that I acquired through building multiple prototypes, I learned a lot about project planning and how to present my ideas to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://martinferianc.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinferianc.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
